OLAWALE FAKOREDE A.

Full Stack Web Developer

Portfolio – https://olawale-fakorede-portfolio.vercel.app/



in https://www.linkedin.com/in/olawale-fakorede



Summary

Meticulous I.T. Personnel with over 4 years of experience interaction with computer. Reviewed written records to verify and transcribe data fields into electronic database. Highly-motivated employee with desire to take on new challenges. Strong worth ethic, adaptability and exceptional interpersonal skills. Adapt at working effectively unsupervised and quickly mastering new skills. High-performing I.T. Personnel with integrity and leadership skills. Applies knowledge and abilities to positively impact on working on I.T. challenges that come my way. Flexible in different situations and dynamics conditions. Works great and well before deadlines. Presently a Full stack developer having different projects with the use of JavaScript, React, creating servers and database and learning new tools as a full stack developer.

Education

. Larva Academy: - Ibadan	2023-2024
Certificate in Full Stack Web Development	
. Federal College of Agriculture: - Moor Plantation, Ibadan Higher National Diploma in Agricultural & Bio-Environmental Engineering.	2018 - 2021
. Federal College of Agriculture: - Moor Plantation, Ibadan Ordinary National Diploma in Agricultural Engineering.	2013-2015
. Centre for Information and Communication Technology: - Ibadan Certificate in ICT Training	2013

Experience

ASSISTANT TUTOR

LARVA ACADEMY OYO, NIGERIA.

August 2024 – TILL DATE

- **Tutoring Javascript**
- Tutoring ReactJs
- Personal/extra teaching with interested students.

A.I/CODING TUTOR

ST' CATHERINE COLLEGE, IBADAN, OYO, NIGERIA.

August 2024 - TILL DATE

March 2023 - Sept 2023

- Teaching tech skills to students.
- Teaching the basic of Frontend web development to students.
- Developing student in different computer based skills.

I.T. PERSONNEL (EXAMS & RECORDS OFFICER)

Lariken International College, Ibadan, Oyo, Nigeria.

- Working on related works on the school website.
- Entry of students' details and management of school website and portal.
- Editing and Formatting of examination questions for all subjects.
- Printing of examination questions for all candidates
- Preparing of Transcript testimonial reference letters and issuing of certificates.
- Registering of student for both Internal and external examinations.

I.T/MEDIA OPERATOR | AAMAC

2018 - TO DATE

- Prepare, edit, entry of data and project all necessary information for each program.
- Identify, diagnose and resolve problems with audio and media systems.
- Place microphones in specific locations to maximize audio quality.
- Supervise crew of audio-video team members.
- Compressed, digitized and duplicate audio ad digital files.
- Installations of software.

https://github.com/Olawale-Fakorede

+2348122422728

Personal Projects

• Personal Portfolio LIVE

A web application that is developed to display my works, sharing my experiences to interested people and allows people to contact me easily.

Technology used for the completion of the project is reactJs.

Dictionary Application

LIVE

A web application used to search for the meaning/definitions, phonetics, examples synonyms and antonyms of English words. Technology used for the completion of the project is reactJs.

• IP Address Tracker LIVE

A web application that helps to track IP Address, with the location and the network used. Technology used for the completion of the project is reactJs.

A School Grading Application

LIVE

A web application that helps calculate scores and give it a remark according to the percentage score by the student. Technology used are HTML, CSS, Media-query and JavaScript are used for the completion of the project.

An Alphabets Learning Web Application

LIVE

This web application is designed for children to help them identify alphabets and examples of what they stand for. A next button and a previous button are embedded for easy scrolling.

Technology used are HTML, CSS, Media-query and JavaScript are used for the completion of the project.

• To-Do List LIVE

The to-do list is a website application built to keep track and monitor daily activities by users Technology used are HTML, CSS, Media-query, and JavaScript are used for the completion of the project.

• Timer LIVE

This works as a normal timer, it counts down the time inputted in the space and it takes the input in seconds and a sound is it attached, when the timer reaches zero the sound alert for the user the time is up.

Technology used are HTML, CSS, Media-query and JavaScript are used for the completion of the project.

Note; more projects are hosted and in my github. (Tic tac toe, accordion, stopwatch etc.)

Technical Skills and Interests

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Front-End: ReactJS, NextJs, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Tailwind, Bootstrap.

Back-End: NodeJS, Express. **Cloud/Databases:** MongoDb.

Hobbies

- Working on a computer
- Surfing and researching from the internet.
- Programming and coding.
- Data Entry
- Formatting of documents.
- Listening to music
- Playing Games